Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Print Advertisements, 1900-1999 and undated RL.11000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Print advertisements
1900-1999
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
RL.11000
15 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The London Office first opened in 1899, and was JWT's first international office as well as the first international office of any American advertising agency.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1900-1999 and includes proofs, storyboards, tear sheets, clippings and some documentation concerning print advertisements produced by JWT's London Office, primarily for clients in the United Kingdom, including Ireland, but also for some campaigns in continental Europe. A small portion of the collection represent advertisements produced or co-produced by the JWT Manchester Office. Clients represented include Addis, the Cheese Bureau, Chesebrough-Pond's, Compari, Elida Gibbs (Unilever), Gallaher, Gramco, ITV, Kellogg's, Rowntree Mackintosh (Nestle), Royal Baking Powder, the Royal Air Force, Trustees' Savings Bank (TSB), and Vaseline. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Arrangement
Arranged into four series: London Office; Manchester Office; Large-format London; and Large-format Manchester.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office Print Advertisements were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1989-2009
Related Materials
Related Materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company London Office Records
J. Walter Thompson Company Newsletter Collection
J. Walter Thompson Company Publications Collection
Advertising agencies -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising -- Great Britain -- History; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Great Britain. Royal Air Force; Nestlé Company; Rowntree Mackintosh Ltd; Gallaher Tobacco; J. Walter Thompson Company; Kellogg Company; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company. Manchester Office; Chesebrough-Pond's.
- London Office, 1900-1997 and undated; 1
  - ABPI (British pharmaceutical industry association) heart disease campaign, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Addis: Baby powder, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Addis: Bride's Guide to Addis, undated (Box 1)
  - Addis: Labels and point-of-purchase, undated (Box 1)
  - Addis: Miscellaneous, 1964-1977 and undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Addis: Radio scripts and storyboards, 1967 and undated (Box 1)
  - Addis: Rave-Sale portfolio, undated (Box 1)
  - Addis: Salesman book, 1971; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Addis: Salesman book, undated (Box 2)
  - Addis: Wisdom toothbrush, 1949, 1966-1971 and undated; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Air-Wick, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Alcan, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Allied Lyons: Skol lager, Hagar the Horrible campaign, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Allied Lyons: Skol lager, Long Life beer, undated (Box 2)
  - Andrex, Puppy Love, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Barclay's Bank, undated (Box 2)
  - British Airports Authority (BAA), 1987 (Box 2)
  - British Fur Trade Association, 1968 (Box 2)
  - British Railways Board, 1985 (Box 2)
  - British Telecom, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Burroughs adding machine, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Butter Information Council, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Campari (Beecham), 1969 (Box 2)
  - Campari (Beecham), 1962-1979 (Box 3)
  - Campbell's, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Creams, 1923-1937, 1954; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Creams, Angel Face, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Testimonial campaign [U.S., Newfoundland, South Africa, New Zealand), 1928 (Box 5)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Two Creams campaign, 1936 (Box 5)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline (includes copy plans and point-of-sale), 1926-1929; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline (includes copy plans and point-of-sale), 1930-1932; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline (includes copy plans and point-of-sale), 1932-1937 (Box 6)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline hair tonic, 1933-1937 (Box 6)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline point-of-purchase, 1920s (Box 7)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's: Vaseline soapless shampoo, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
  - Cuticura Laboratories, Ayds Trimwheel exercise equipment, 1970 (Box 7)
  - Daily Express, 1971 (Box 7)
  - DeBeers, 1969-1997 (Box 7)
  - DeVere Hotels, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1971 (Box 7)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever): All Clear shampoo, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever): Harmony hair color, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever): Sun Silk, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever): Timotei shampoo, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever): Wood Nymph Blonde, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Europa (furniture), 1968 (Box 7)
  - Europa (furniture), point of sale, 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Findus (frozen foods), 1968 (Box 7)
  - Ford, Escort and Orion, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Gallaher: Amber Leaf, Berkeley Superkings, 1991 and undated (Box 8)
  - Gallaher: Kensitas Club, 1985-1986 and undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Gallaher: Old Holborn, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Gallaher: Rolled Gold, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Gallaher: Sullivan Powell, undated (Box 8)
  - General Motors, Cadillac/Chevrolet, 1920s (Box 8)
  - Gillette: International, including Bright Promise Cream, Gillette Club Cricket, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Gillette: Newsprint, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Gillette: Storyboards and printed material, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps, undated (Box 8)
  - Gramco (investments), 1970; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Guardian (newspaper), tube and bus posters, 1981 and undated (Box 8)
  - Guinness, 1969, 1976; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Hoechst, Taravio, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Horlick's, including Nulacin, 1932, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Insuramatic, 1984 (Box 8)
  - ITV, 1989 and undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - J. Walter Thompson, 1957-1990 (Box 9)
  - Kellogg's: All-Bran, Bran Buds, Corn Flakes, Special K, 1954-1988 (Box 9)
  - Kellogg's: Frosties, Richard Purdum Productions transparencies, undated (Box 9)
  - Kellogg's: Frosties, Tony the Tiger sketches, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Kellogg's: Packaging: Crunchy Nut Corn Flakes, Golden Crackles, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Kraft: Cheddar cheese, 1929 (Box 9)
  - Kraft: Ranch dressing, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Lever Brothers (Unilever), Lux Flakes, 1900 (Box 9)
  - Mackeson's Milk Stout, 1937-1957 (Box 9)
  - Muscular Dystrophy, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Natwest (National Westminster Bank), London and Manchester Office, 1969-1989 (Box 9)
  - Pan American World Airways, 1954 (Box 9)
  - Parker Pen, 1954-1969 (Box 9)
  - Pfizer, Feldene, 1980s (Box 9)
  - Rhone-Poulenc Rorer, Oruvail, 1993 (Box 9)
  - Quilted Fiesta, 1984 (Box 9)
  - Reckitt-Colman, Colman's Mustard, Sanpic disinfectant, 1954, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Rolex, 1979-1988 (Box 9)
  - Rowntree Mackintosh: Black Magic, Kit Kat, Pan Yan, After Eight, Polo, 1933-1989 (Box 9)
  - Rowntree Mackintosh: Smarties, Kit Kat, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Royal Air Force, circa 1988 (Box 9)
  - Royal Baking Powder, 1931-1936; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Scott Paper, includes Scotties tissues, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Silhouette (lingerie), 1970 (Box 11)
  - Smith and Nephew, Elastoplast bandages, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Squibb, Granuflex, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Standard Brands, African campaigns in Kenya, Uganda, Tanzania, 1954 (Box 11)
  - Strongbow ale, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Stock Exchange, 1969-1976; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Swaddlers' Togs (children's clothes), 1989 (Box 11)
  - Swakara (furs), 1969-1976; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Taunton cider, 1972-1977 (Box 11)
  - Taylor Woodrow, Anderson Cross Center, undated (Box 11)
  - Thomson Holidays, 1984 (Box 12)
  - TSB (Trustees' Savings Bank), includes TSB Group and Trustcard, 1985-1989 and undated; 8 folders (Box 12)
  - TSB (Trustees' Savings Bank) transit cards, circa 1989 (Box 19)
  - Tycom, 1982 (Box 12)
  - Unigate, St. Ivel Gold lowfat spread, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Brooke Bond Oxo, Fray Bentos, Sun Witch, Timotei, Harmony, 1968-1989 (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Lux, Persil, 1932-1991 (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Oxo, Daily Mirror souvenir edition, 1960 Sept. 2 (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Persil, 1952-1956 (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Persil posters, undated, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Unilever: Rinso, 1931-1937 (Box 12)
  - Warner-Lambert--Clorets, Listerine, Mentholatease, 1981-1990 (Box 12)
  - Warner-Wellcome, Anusol Plus, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Wine and Spirit Association of Great Britain, 1953-1961 (Box 12)
- Manchester Office, 1981-1990; 2
  - ASDA supermarkets, circa 1984 (Box 13)
  - Baxi (boilers), 1987-1990 (Box 13)
  - Co-Operative Retail Services/Leo's Supermarkets, 1987-1989 (Box 13)
  - Greenall Whitley Group (Greenall's Original bitter), 1989 (Box 13)
  - Guardian and Manchester Evening News, 1981, 1990 (Box 13)
  - Hanson, New Era (homeopathic preparations), 1990 (Box 13)
  - Holt Lloyd International, Redex (automotive engine detergent), 1989 (Box 13)
  - Magnet and Southerns (kitchens), 1984 (Box 13)
  - Norcros, Cristal (ceramic tile), 1987-1988 (Box 13)
  - Northern Electric/Northern Telecom, 1988-1990 (Box 13)
  - Pilkington Brothers (eyeglasses), 1985-1990 (Box 13)
  - Sharp electronics, 1987-1990 (Box 13)
  - Swinton Insurance Group, 1988-1989 (Box 13)
  - Thorn EMI/Focus (home entertainment centers), 1985 (Box 13)
  - Warrington-Buncorn (The Development Corporation), 1988 (Box 13)
  - Yorkshire Building Society, 1988 (Box 13)
- Large Format--London, 1960-1999 and undated; 3
  - Addis, 1965-1971 and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Alcan, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Allied Lyons: Cockburn's Reserve Port, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Allied Lyons: Skol lager, Hagar the Horrible campaign, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Barclay's Bank, undated (Box 14)
  - British Airports Authority (BAA), 1987 (Box 14)
  - British Airways, Enterprise Holidays, newsprint, 1974 (Box 14)
  - British Telecom, 1985-1988 (Box 14)
  - Butter Information Council, 1969-1970 (Box 14)
  - Canary Wharf, undated (Box 14)
  - Cheese Bureau, 1970s (Box 14)
  - Chesebrough-Pond's, Eastmam Kodak newsprint, 1960s (Box 14)
  - Children's Foundation, undated (Box 14)
  - DeBeers, 1987, 1999 (Box 14)
  - E. Gomme Ltd, G-Plan furniture, circa 1960 (Box 14)
  - Elida Gibbs (Unilever)--All-Clear, Harmony, 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Europa (furniture), 1969 and undated (Box 14)
  - Findus (frozen foods), 1970 (Box 14)
  - Findus (frozen foods), newsprint, 1970 (Box 14)
  - Ford, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Furniture Circle, undated (Box 14)
  - Gallaher: Kensitas Club, 1985 and undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Gallaher: Niemeyer, Samson tobacco, undated (Box 15)
  - Gillette, international, 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Golden Wonder Crisps, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Gramco (investments), 1970; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Guinness, 1976 and undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - H.P. Bulmer, Strongbow, undated (Box 15)
  - Hi-Tec (footwear), 1990 (Box 15)
  - Inchape, 1970 (Box 15)
  - ITV, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
  - J&B scotch, circa 1999 (Box 15)
  - Jaguar, circa 1999 (Box 15)
  - J. Walter Thompson: Agency of the Year, 1991 (Box 15)
  - J. Walter Thompson: Jeremy Bullmore poster, 1980 (Box 15)
  - J. Walter Thompson: Losing Guinness, 1982 (Box 15)
  - J. Walter Thompson: Recruitment, 1991 (Box 15)
  - J. Walter Thompson: Silver Jubilee, 1977 (Box 15)
  - Kellogg's--All-Bran psa, Crunchy Nut Corn Flakes, 1987 and undated (Box 15)
  - Kit-Kat (Nestle, Rowntree Mackintosh), circa 1999 (Box 15)
  - Madame Toussaud's, circa 1999 (Box 15)
  - Muscular Dystrophy, 1984 (Box 15)
  - National Lottery, undated (Box 16)
  - Natwest (National Westminster Bank), 1984-1989 and undated (Box 16)
  - Observer, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Parker Pen, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Pfizer, Feldene, 1980s (Box 16)
  - Procter & Gamble, Tog's Nappies (diapers), undated (Box 16)
  - Professional and Executive Recruitment (PER), 1973 (Box 16)
  - Reader's Digest, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Rowntree Mackintosh: After Eight, Dairy Box, Polo, 1984-1990 and undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Royal Air Force, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Silhouette (lingerie), 1970 (Box 16)
  - SmithKline Beecham, Hepatitis B psa, undated (Box 16)
  - Swakara (furs), undated (Box 16)
  - Teacher's scotch, undated (Box 16)
  - TSB (Trustees' Savings Bank), includes TSB Group and Trustcard, 1980s and undated; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Tycom, 1982 (Box 16)
  - Unilever: Lux, Shield, KC, Lifebuoy bar soaps, 1988 and undated (Box 16)
  - Unilever: Oxo, 1984-1988 (Box 16)
  - Unilever: Persil, 1984-1988 and undated; 4 folders (Box 16)
- Large Format--Manchester, 1984-1991; 4
  - ASDA supermarkets, circa 1984 (Box 16)
  - British Gas, Northeastern, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Co-Operative Retail Services/Leo's Supermarkets, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Greenall Whitley Group (Greenall's Original bitter), 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Guardian and Manchester Evening News, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Natwest (National Westminster Bank), 1987 (Box 16)
  - Norcros, Cristal (ceramic tile), 1989 (Box 16)
  - Piccadilly Radio, circa 1984 (Box 16)
  - Sharp electronics, 1989-1991 (Box 16)
- Large Format--London, 1984-1991; 5
  - Guinness: Gilroy poster transparencies, undated (Box 17)
  - Guiness: Promotional calendars, 1970-1980 (Box 17)
  - Addis, undated (Box 18)
  - Allied Lyons--Skol lager, Hagar the Horrible campaign, 1986 (Box 18)
  - British Airways, Enterprise Holidays, 1974; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Butter Information Council, Homepride, undated (Box 18)
  - Canary Wharf, undated (Box 18)
  - Cheese Bureau, 1970 and undated (Box 18)
  - Europa (furniture), 1969-1970 (Box 18)
  - Father Thames (restaurant), undated (Box 18)
  - Gallaher: Kensitas Club, undated, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Gallaher: Lloyd's Old Holborn, undated (Box 18)
  - J. Walter Thompson, Agency of the Year, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Rowntree Mackintosh--Dairy Box, Kit-Kat, Lion, Polo, undated (Box 18)
  - Royal Air Force, undated (Box 18)
  - Royal Mail Parcel Force, undated (Box 18)
  - Teacher's scotch, undated (Box 18)
  - TSB Group, undated (Box 18)
  - Unilever--Persil, undated (Box 18)